Roxane Connick Carlisle collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Roxane Connick Carlisle collection 1963-1984
AFC 2012/008
Carlisle, Roxane Connick
3007 items
876 sheets
190 sound tapes (reels, cassettes): analog; various sizes
1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm; 12 in.
2 videocassettes (VHS): sound, color; 1/2 in.
1 videocassette (U-Matic): sound, color; 3/4 in.
1 film reel
1532 photographs: slides, black-and-white, color
278 photographic prints: black-and white, color; various sizes
24 contact sheets: black-and white
101 negative strips: black-and white; 35 mm
1 artifact
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of field recordings, photographs, video recordings, a film, and manuscripts created by Roxane Connick Carlisle primarily in Darfur Province and other locations in the Sudan region, which now includes South Sudan, from 1963-1968. The collection also includes photographs of musicians, musical instruments, markets, gardens, buildings, weddings, and wildlife taken in Sudan, Somalia, Kenya, and Uganda from 1963-1968. Includes field recordings of music of various groups and photographs of musicians including Anuak, Baggara, Beni Halba, Bederiya, Dinka, Fur, Nuer, Ingessana, Shilluk, Ta'isha, Zaghawa, and other people, documenting wedding music, women's song and poetry traditions, and other music and ceremonies. The collection includes eight audio tape reels of oud music, songs, and interviews with noted Sudanese musician Abdel Karim el Kably recorded in 1963. The collection also includes recordings of the radio series, Listen to the World from 1971-1973, broadcast on CHEX-FM, Peterborough, Ontario. The shows were produced, written, and narrated by Roxane Connick Carlisle. Sound recordings for radio programs, demonstration, and teaching ethnomusicology include music from Afghanistan, other locations in Africa (Ethiopia, Burundi, and more), Australia and Papua New Guinea, Brazil, Bulgaria, China, India, Indonesia, Japan, North American Indian, Philippines, Polynesia, Southeast Asia, and Spain, and include recordings for Alan Lomax's Cantometrics project. The collection includes recordings of several speeches and interviews by Roxane Carlisle, including her interview with Ahmed Diraige, governor of Darfur, March 1983.
Provenance
Roxane Connick Carlisle; 2012.
Accruals
No accruals are expected.
Related Material
Sudanese music performed by Abdel Karim Al-Kabli (AFC 2015/045), American Folklife Center, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. This collection contains materials documenting a concert held in the Whittall Pavilion co-sponsored by the Library of Congress and the American Folklife Center featuring Abdel Karim Al-Kabli.
Audiovisual Archives at the Canadian Museum of History (formerly the Canadian Museum of Civilization). The Archives keeps a set of Carlisle's field recordings.
University of Khartoum. Sudan Research Unit. The University keeps a set of Carlisle's field recordings.
Access and Restrictions
The Roxanne Connick Carlisle collection is open for research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Roxane Connick Carlisle has served as President of the Institute for Development of Education through the Arts (1987-1990), worked as Special Advisor to the President on the Integration of Women in Development, Canadian International Development Agency (CIDA; 1976-1983), and taught anthropology at Trent University, Peterborough, Ontario, Canada (1970-1972), in addition to other roles in sponsored travel and research (including a Fulbright Fellowship, 1962-1963). She did fieldwork in 1963 and 1967 in various areas of the Sudan, before South Sudan gained its independence, and documented various aspects of cultural traditions for several tribes. She has worked for the Canadian International Development Agency, in part to provide research and guidance towards programs that improve the welfare of women in developing countries. As an ethnomusicologist and educator, she has published works that support the inclusion of world music in universities. Her radio program, Listen to the World was an early introduction to world music for a general audience. Carlisle's career has been, in its many aspects, a means by which traditions on the verge of change are documented, maintained (in memory if not in practice), and shared with various audiences.
Scope and Content
Collection of field recordings, photographs, video recordings, a film, and manuscripts created by Roxane Connick Carlisle primarily in Darfur Province and other locations in the Sudan region, which now includes South Sudan, from 1963-1968. The collection also includes photographs of musicians, musical instruments, markets, gardens, buildings, weddings, and wildlife taken in Sudan, Somalia, Kenya, and Uganda from 1963-1968. Includes field recordings of music of various groups and photographs of musicians including Anuak, Baggara, Beni Halba, Bederiya, Dinka, Fur, Nuer, Ingessana, Shilluk, Ta'isha, Zaghawa, and other people, documenting wedding music, women's song and poetry traditions, and other music and ceremonies. The collection includes eight audio tape reels of oud music, songs, and interviews with noted Sudanese musician Abdel Karim el Kably recorded in 1963. The collection also includes recordings of the radio series, Listen to the World from 1971-1973, broadcast on CHEX-FM, Peterborough, Ontario. The shows were produced, written, and narrated by Roxane Connick Carlisle. Sound recordings for radio programs, demonstration, and teaching ethnomusicology include music from Afghanistan, other locations in Africa (Ethiopia, Burundi, and more), Australia and Papua New Guinea, Brazil, Bulgaria, China, India, Indonesia, Japan, North American Indian, Philippines, Polynesia, Southeast Asia, and Spain, and include recordings for Alan Lomax's Cantometrics project. The collection includes recordings of several speeches and interviews by Roxane Carlisle, including her interview with Ahmed Diraige, governor of Darfur, March 1983.
Arrangement
Organized by format into the following series:
Series 1: Manuscripts
Series 2. Sound recordings
Series 3. Photographs
Series 4. Moving image items
Series 5. Artifacts
For more selected search terms, see Appendix A for ethnic groups, and Appendix B for musical instruments.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Carlisle, Roxane Connick; Carlisle, Roxane Connick--Ethnomusicological collections.; Kābilī, ʻAbd al-Karīm, 1933-; Kābilī, ʻAbd al-Karīm--Interviews.; Turnbull, Colin M.--Photographs.
Subjects
Anuak (African people)--Social life and customs--Photographs.; Arabs--South Sudan--Music.; Arabs--Sudan--Music.; Baggara (African people)--Music.; Dinka (African people)--Social life and customs--Photographs.; Ethnomusicology.; Folk music--Sudan.; Fur (African people)--Music.; Hamar (African people)--Music.; Music--South Sudan; Music--Sudan.; Musical instruments--South Sudan.; Musical instruments--Sudan.; Nuer (African people)--Social life and customs--Photographs.; Päri (African people)--Social life and customs--Photographs.; Shilluk (African people)--Social life and customs--Photographs.; Songs, Arabic.; Taaisha (African people)--Music.; Wedding music.; Weddings--South Sudan.; Weddings--Sudan.; Women singers--Sudan.; Zaghawa (African people)--Music.
Places
Dārfūr al-Janūbīyah (Sudan: Province); Dārfūr al-Shamālīyah (Sudan: Province); South Sudan--Social life and customs.; Sudan (Region); Sudan--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Field recordings.; Folk music radio programs.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Photographs--Color--1960-1970.; Songs.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence and professional activities
    - Correspondence, 1968-2011, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
      Handwritten and typed correspondence from John Majok Bol and other Sudanese correspondents, Curt Wittig (Director, Traditional Music Documentation Project), and from Carlisle to staff at the American Folklife Center who would be processing her collection.
    - Field notes: Sudan, 1963 (Box-folder 1/2)
      Photocopied and original handwritten notes.
    - Field notes: Sudan, 1967 (Box-folder 1/3)
      Photocopied, handwritten notes.
    - "The current ethnomusicology curriculum in Canadian universities," by Roxane C. Carlisle (two copies), September 1972 (Box-folder 1/4)
      Offprint from Ethnomusicology, vol. XVI, no. 3.
    - "Women singers in Darfur, Sudan Republic," by Roxane Connick Carlisle (two copies), 1973 (Box-folder 1/5)
      Offprint from Anthropos: International review of ethnology and linguistics, vol. 68.
    - "Folk music in Canada," by Roxane Carlisle, February 28, 1974 (Box-folder 1/6)
      Uncorrected proof from the Canadian Centre for Folk Culture Studies, National Museum of Man, National Museums of Canada.
    - Carlisle's notes from her classroom lectures, 1975-1984, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
      Typed and handwritten notes on index cards and sheets of paper; some photocopied, handwritten notes. The majority of materials are undated.
    - Interview questions for videotaping session with H.E. Ahmed Diraige, April 11, 1984 (Box-folder 1/8)
      4 index cards with handwritten notes.
    - Carlisle's curriculum vitae, circa 1991 (Box-folder 1/9)
      10 typed pages.
  - Subseries 2: Documentation from containers for sound recordings
    - SR001-SR071 (Box-folder 1/10)
      Typed and handwritten notes.
    - SR072-SR089 (Box-folder 1/11)
      See the note for box-folder 1/10.
    - SR090-SR112 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - SR114-SR191 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Subseries 3: Documentation from containers for photographs and moving image items
    - PH0001-PH0074: Amin family - private activities at home in Omdurman (Box-folder 2/1)
    - PH0075-PH0149: Awad el Karim - Omdurman I (Box-folder 2/2)
    - PH0150-PH0223: Awad el Karim - Omdurman I (Box-folder 2/3)
    - PH0224-PH0300: Dinka and Nuer (Box-folder 2/4)
    - PH0301-PH0321: Ethnomusicology I, Sudan, 1963 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - PH0322-PH0365: Ethnomusicology II, Sudan, 1963 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - PH0366-PH0442: Mahdi family I (Box-folder 2/7)
    - PH0403-PH0503: Mahdi family II (Box-folder 2/8)
    - PH0504-PH0588: Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill, Equatoria province, 1963 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - PH0589-PH0666: Republic of Sudan I, 1963 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - PH0667-PH0736: Republic of Sudan II, 1963 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - PH0737-PH0804: Upper Nile Province, Sudan, 1963 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - PH0805-PH0872: Upper Nile Province - Malakal, 1963 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - PH0873-PH0927: Upper Nile Province - Akurwa and Fashoda, 1963 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - PH0928-PH0984: Upper Nile Province - Kodoc, the court with the Reth, 1963 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - PH0985-PH1035: Yahia wedding, Omdurman, 1963 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Photo album (photocopies of pages as received): PH1585-PH1787, PH1809-PH1810 1963 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - MV01-MV03: photocopied documentation, 1963 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Subseries 4: Oversize materials
    - "Sudanese women: what can our ideas of emancipation give them that they do not already enjoy?", 3 legal-size manuscript pages. (Box-folder 3/1)
    - PH1036-PH1128: documentation (Box-folder 3/2)
    - PH1561-PH1584: documentation (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Documentation from wooden boxes that held slides (Box-folder 3/4)
- Series 2: Sound recordings
  The recordings that have been digitized have not been processed, and the ID numbers differ from their analog sources.
  - Subseries 1: Field recordings, demonstration tapes, and other compilations
    - Interview with Col. Osman Amin in his home, in Omdurman, March 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 5 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR001)
      Roxane's interview of Col. Osman Amin about Sudanese dress, names of garments. Interview terminated abruptly when his sister Bakhita called Roxane to lunch.
    - Mahdi women's songs, wedding, March 31, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR002)
      Recorded in Omdurman, at the home of Saadig el Mahdi.
    - Shilluk 1, April 7, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR005)
      Songs, with singing and drums.
    - Shilluk 3, April 6, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR004)
      Interview with Eduard Umum, mayor of Lelo Omodia, on veranda of Emir Orner [?] el Tinay (district commissioner of Shilluk territory).
    - Shilluk 5, April 7, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR006)
      General ceremonial gathering, at Kadoc. Occasion: World Health Organization celebration. Exhibitions and speech.
    - Shilluk 6, April 7, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR007)
      At Kadoc: traditional songs and one modern song.
    - Shilluk 7, April 7, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR008)
      At Kadoc: songs; one includes elbow bells and drums.
    - Shilluk 8, April 8, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track, mono; 5 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR009)
      At Kadoc: songs, some with soloists, mixed chorus, elbow bells, bul drum. Eduard Umum provides commentaries.
    - Shilluk 9, April 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR010)
      At Kadoc: songs, some with soloists, mixed chorus, elbow bells, bul drum. Eduard Umum provides explanations and answers questions.
    - Shilluk 10, April 30, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR012)
      Shilluk Thom, recorded in Malakal in the home of Col. Osman Nasr Osman. Songs, with extraneous background noises of the household (chickens, etc.).
    - Shilluk 11, April 23, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR011)
      Akurwa in Northern Shilluk territory; in front of shrine. Includes spoken passages by the Reth.
    - Anuak, Akobo 1, April 14, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR013)
      Recorded in the garden of Victor Bol: six songs with ladies chorus, three drums, and antelope horn.
    - Anuak, Akobo 2, April 16, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR014)
      Recorded in the home of Victor Bol, Akobo. 12 selections of solo singers.
    - Anuak, Akobo 3, April 17, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR015)
      Recorded in Upper Nile Province, Republic of Sudan. 6 songs.
    - Anuak, Akobo 4, April 17, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR016)
      Recorded in Akobo, Upper Nile Province, Republic of Sudan.
    - Nuer, Akobo, April 15, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR017)
      Nuer lyre songs recorded in Akobo, at the home of Victor Bol.
    - Nuer, Akobo, April 15, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR018)
      Recorded at Akobo, Upper Nile Province, Republic of Sudan. Women's and men's chorus and drums. 11 selections.
    - Nuer, Akobo: roam lyre songs, April 15, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track, mono; 5 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR019)
      Recorded in Akobo, Upper Nile Province, at the home of Victor Bol.
      Processor's note: the name Bol is pronounced approximately like the name Paul, and the name Victor Paul has been corrected to Victor Bol in one instance; elsewhere in this document it has been corrected silently.
    - Nuer, Dinka, April 15, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR020)
      Nuer, recorded at various campsites in Upper Nile. Dinka recorded in camps near Akobo and Bantiu.
    - Dinka, Akobo, April 16, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR021)
      Includes praise to Dinka chief, to show variations of choral litany responses.
    - Dinka, Wau district, Rumbek subdistrict, May 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR022)
      Recent Dinka praise songs from Wau, composed in 1962 for President Abboud. Recorded in the Wau district, Rumbek subdistrict. Copied from tapes in the Sudan Broadcasting library, Izza, Khartoum.
    - Dinka - Bantiu, May 2, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR023)
      Fariang (Riangnam) village with military governor and convoy, welcome of governor and special dances of Dinka women and men, etc. Tape has some wind noise but good drumming and choral passages.
    - 1. Kordofan, Nuba Mountains 2. Nuer 3. Dinka, May 2, 1963 - May 3, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR024)
      Dance, singers, etc.
    - Kordofan Fellata nomads, Lake Abyad, May 5, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR025)
      White Lake (Abyad Lake), Upper Nile Province. Fellata dances of men and women with two drums for Col. Osman and party, held on shores of Lake Abyad with Dinka observers.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 1, May 11, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR026)
      Songs of mourning or Doodi Taw recorded in morning session with chief Ufure Kiri and Benedetto interpreting, etc.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 2, May 11-12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR027)
      Mixed chorus in evening and girls's chorus in morning.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 3, May 12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR028)
      Girls's chorus. 10 songs; last two accompanied by clapping.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 4 (Puchwa section), May 12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR029)
      Pot drums and singing.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 1, May 11, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR030)
      Songs of mourning or doodi taw recorded in morning session with chief Ufure Kiri and Benedetto interpreting. Women's and men's chorus with tung horn. No song titles.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 2, May 11-12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR031)
      Mixed chorus in the evening and girls's chorus in the morning.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 3, May 12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR032)
      Girls's chorus. 10 songs; the last two accompanied by clapping.
    - Pari Lokoro of Lafon Hill 4, May 12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR033)
      5 clay pot drums recorded in Puchwa section of Lafon Hill.
    - Omdurman wedding, May 24, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR034)
      Khartoum North, wedding party. Ibrahim Awad and musicians playing 11:30 p.m. on at second day of marriage celebration.
    - Ahmed Mustafa, songs I, May 25, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR035)
      Ahmed el Mustafa, recorded in Omdurman compound of Amin family before buffet dinner given by Bakhita Amin for Carlisle.
    - Ahmed Mustafa, songs II, May 25, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR036)
      Ahmed el Mustafa, recorded in Omdurman compound of Amin family at private dinner party given by Bakhita Amin for Carlisle.
    - Ajali wedding songs, Omdurman, June 2, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR037)
      Wedding party of Mahaesin and Mohammed Idriss in the Awad el Karim compound. Ajali wedding songs sung by an Ajali tribesman from northeastern Sudan to the accompaniment of a dluka earthenware drum and several other singers.
    - Wedding party in Omdurman, Ayub Farris singer, Toum Hassan ud player, four songs, June 2, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR038)
      Wedding party recorded at the home of the Awad el Karim of Mahaesin and Muhammed Idriss.
    - Omdurman, wedding songs, June 2, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR039)
      Djertig ceremony - wedding of Hayat Awad el Karim's cousin Mahaesin to Muhammed Idriss.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #1, June 10, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR040)
      In Omdurman. First afternoon.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #2, June 10, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR041)
      In Omdurman. First evening: Sayed Khalifa with his ud, two violinists, and congo drums.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #3, June 10, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR042)
      In Omdurman. First evening: Sayed Khalifa and others.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #4, June 11, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR043)
      In Omdurman. Second evening: male singers from Berber and Omdurman.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #5, June 12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR044)
      In Omdurman. Third evening party: various traditional love songs for wedding party.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #6, June 13, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR046)
      Fourth evening party: the djertig or milk-blowing ceremony.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #7, June 13, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR047)
      Fourth evening party: El Jali (folk singer), with dluka drum and two accompanying singers.
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #8, June 12, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR048)
      Fourth evening party: El Jali (folk singer), with dluka drum and two accompanying singers, and a member of the Ja'alin tribe (professional wedding singer). Roxane spells the name "Ja'alyin."
    - Hayat and Abdulmagid's wedding #9: ahmadiya zikker ritual, June 13, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR045)
      In Omdurman. Fourth day: the djertig or milk blowing ceremony.
    - Ratib of the Mahdi, June 30, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR049)
      Chanting of the full sacred devotional text known as the Ratib of the Mahdi, by Fiqi Abdullaki.
    - Ratib of the Mahdi, June 30, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track, mono; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR050)
      Ratib of the Mahdi, intoned by Fiqi Abdullaki, in Omdurman at the home of el Sayed Saadig el Mahdi.
    - Amin wedding, Omdurman (tape 1), July 1, 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, 1 track; 7 in. (Item id AFC 2012/008: SR051)
      First wedding party of the wedding week of poet and author Hassan Amin, brother of Col. Osman Amin, in the Amin compound in Omdurman.